# 這個小黑的崽
This is Blacky's child.
# 那麼胖的哦
He's so fat now.
# 小黑
Blacky!
# 一身肥膘
He's covered with fat.
# 不知道為甚麼它吃的[SIC]那麼胖
I have no ideas why he is that fat.
# 別的都沒那麼大
The others are not that big.
# 就它的那 就它這隻那麼大
But he is, this is exceptionally big.
# 它太能吃啦 可能
He is a big eater, perhaps.
# 吃太多啦
He eats too much.
# 你看一下你 長了多少個月
Look at yourself! How old are you?
# 長了半年啦 沒人家大
You're already half a year old now, but still not as big as him.
# 人家才一個多月 就長成這樣子啦
He's just a month old, and is already that big now.
# 哦
Oh!
# 小黑
Blacky!
# 你看 它的爪子
Look! His paws are,
# 好大啊 它的爪子
so big, his paws.
# 比別人胖了一半
He's one and a half of the others' sizes.
# 它這個毛豎起來的
His fur is standing up.
# 其實沒那麼胖的
In fact he's not really that fat.
# 看上去就那麼胖
But he looks really chubby.
# 它也不叫了哦
He's not yelping anymore.
# 以前它 我一摸它 它就
He used to start screaming immediately whenever,
# 開始叫起來 現在它都不叫啦
whenever I touched him. But now he's not screaming anymore.
# 跟我熟悉啦
He knows me well now.
# 哦 小狗
Oh! Puppy!
# 你看它 眼睛
Look at him, his eyes are
# 默默無聞的
speechless.
# 是啊
Indeed.
# 隨便你把它怎麼樣都行
You can simply do whatever you like on him.
# 它 反正它就是 不反抗 (註︰把這兩句合一較易處理)
He's, he's not fighting back anyway.
# 吃的好多哇
He eats so much.
# 撓它痒痒它也沒反應
He has no response even if I tickle him.
# 要聽話哦
Be a good boy! Got it?
# 不聽話我就把你
Otherwise I'll,
# 拿來送人
give you to other people,
# 送給兄弟
to my buddy.
# 不知不道
Got it?
# 等天晴啦 我把它洗一下澡 (註︰他的洗澡應該只是拋到河裡洗兩下)
I'll bathe you when it's sunny.
# 看著我幹嘛
Why are you looking at me?
# 給你洗一個澡 看你一身
I said I'll bathe you. You see you're,
# 一身都好髒
you're covered with dirt.
# 從出生到現在都沒有洗過澡
You've never taken a bath since you were born.
# 它一直看著我
He keeps staring at me.
# 怎麼 不認識我一樣
It's like, as if he doesn't know me.
# 天天餵你
I feed you everyday.
# 你怎麼不認識我
You should know me well.
# 呵呵 腳翹起來 不敢動
Hm hm, he stretches his legs straight, and dares not move.
# 你是不是不敢動嗎
Don't you dare to move?
# 小黑
Blacky,
# 這是你的崽
this is your boy.
# 就是你把它餵的那麼胖的
Because of you, he's so fat now.